#### LAWRENCE AGBANI

Address: Moosacher str. 10A, 80809 Munich, Germany

**Tel:** +4917685619704

Email: l.agbani@hotmail.co.uk, agbani92@gmail.com

**StackOverflow**: <a href="https://stackoverflow.com/users/3496905/lawrenceagani">https://stackoverflow.com/users/3496905/lawrenceagani</a>

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/lawrenceagbani

#### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I am a cross functional engineer with a strong background in Agile software engineering and over 4 years of experience using PHP, C#, Javascript (NodeJs) and Java. I am a strong-willed and determined individual, having been exposed to different social and working environments I have developed quite a lot of skills both personally and professionally. One thing I believe is that challenges can only strengthen my abilities and not bring me down. Most of my experiences are based on backend web development and Android. I love solving problems and learning recent technologies especially in web and mobile.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

## **WESTWING GROUP AG, MUNICH, GERMANY**

#### **Software Engineer:**

September 2018 - Present

I work as a Software Engineer for the company where I perform the following tasks:

- Work on maintaining and building new features for the suite of logistics applications used by the supply chain team
- Improve performance of the API project serving the customer facing applications
- Participate in code reviews to ensure standards are met from other contributors to these projects
- Participate in meetings with stakeholders to understand change/feature requests

### **DEIMOS COMPANY, CAPE TOWN, SOUTH AFRICA**

#### **Software Engineer (remote consultant):**

February 2019 - Present

I work as a Software Engineer for the company where I perform the following tasks:

- Work with clients on various technologies. Here, I do a bit of devops and a lot of coding with dotnet, php and nodejs.

## KONGA ONLINE SHOPPING LIMITED, LAGOS, NIGERIA (www.konga.com)

**Software Engineering Team Lead (Logistics and ERP)**: January 2018 – August 2018

I worked as a Team Lead for the company where I perform the following tasks:

- Work on maintaining and building new features for the logistics applications used by the franchisees and internal users.
- Work on maintaining and building new features for services built around the ERP solution (SAP).
- Mentor Junior Engineers and be responsible for them all through their probationary period, and after that.
- Evaluate current business processes and recommend solutions for improvements.
- Develop and maintain best practices to meet changing business needs.

# **Software Engineer:**

December 2016 – December 2017

I worked as a Software Engineer for the company where I perform the following tasks:

- Work with an Agile team to transform the monolithic <u>www.konga.com</u> to Microservice (SOA) Architecture.
- Design and develop performance critical applications and services in PHP, nodejs and .NET to improve e-commerce operations.
- Write unit tests to test new modules.
- Understand trends from merchants and warehouse processing from data analysis in order to implement features to ensure seamless warehouse operations and merchants' seamless use of <a href="https://www.konga.com">www.konga.com</a>.
- Mentor Interns and junior engineers.
- Code optimization for scale.

# **FOREFRONT AGENCY INC (www.forefront.co)**

### **Senior Software Engineer:**

February 2016 - November 2016

I worked as a Software Engineer for the company where I perform the following tasks:

- Recommended best-practices for design and implementation of new software projects.
- Code reviewed other engineers code via team collaboration tool git and bitbucket.
- Interfaced with clients for requirements gathering.
- Translated business requirements to stories using Jira Atlassian and Trello boards.
- Created database and table schema, including relational and document type database.
- Scheduled sprints and coordinated team stand-up meetings.
- Coordinated agile tests of features, improvements and bug fixes.
- Wrote server side code using PHP, C# or Nodejs based on client requests, front-end code using html, css, javascript, jQuery.
- Also wrote Android apps using Java or Xamarin for cross platform based on client requests as well.
- Worked alongside other developers to write bank end logics including Rest apis, database setup.
- Maintained legacy codes.
- Created project schedule and managed change requests.

## TALENTBASE NIGERIA, LAGOS, NIGERIA (www.talentbase.ng)

# **Software Engineer Intern:**

May 2015 - February 2016

I worked as a Software Engineer for the company where I perform the following tasks:

- Database design and implementation. Developed Android applications that called APIs from the web platform (www.talentbase.ng).
- I used Java (For android), php and mysql(Codeigniter framework) for development during my time with the company and used Amazon Web Service cloud platform.
- I built some modules available on the web app(HR platform) for the mobile app, calling the APIs provided, and creating APIs where necessary.

### **MICROSOFT, LAGOS, NIGERIA**

#### **Lead Microsoft Student Partner**

May 2014 - May 2015

I worked as a Student Partner on the following tasks:

- Hosting technology events on campuses.
- Speaking in technical events.
- Creating and maintaining technical communities where I trained developers on using Microsoft Technologies.
- I built apps using C#, ASP.NET, WPF, Windows Forms, Windows services and Xamarin. I focused on building APIs at some point and worked with the Microsoft Developer Experience team on a few projects.
- I used the Microsoft Azure cloud technology and also trained developers on how to provision and deploy apps to virtual machines on there.

**Team Lead** for Team Innovation, second runners-up at the 2014 Microsoft Game Jam Challenge Tinapa, Calabar, Nigeria – June 2014:

At this event we built a flappy bird clone with tools provided by the Microsoft Developer Experience staff.

# **NEXT INTEGRATED SYSTEMS, OWERRI, IMO STATE, NIGERIA**

**Data Collection/Analysis Personnel** for Team Nixit, winners at the 2014 Nasa Space Apps challenge Lagos, Nigeria – April 2014 (<a href="https://www.2014.spaceappschallenge.org">www.2014.spaceappschallenge.org</a>):

I and the team built an Android application we called "My Earth Observer" under the "animate your world" category. The application was built to enhance precision agriculture by enabling farmers view and section out their farm lands from their mobile phone, alongside other use cases.

### **Software Developer:**

September 2013 – March 2015

Maintained the mobile app, Health Mobile with the team. I took part in the backend and server side design of the mobile app (using PHP) which can be found on the Google Playstore.

Consumed external APIs that gave health information and parsed these responses on the app.

I took part in sprint planning and implementation of new features.

#### **EDUCATION**

Soil Science and Technology B.Tech., Federal University of Technology, Owerri (FUTO).

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

Microsoft Certified Technology Associate (MCTA, 386-761).

Microsoft Certified Professional: Architecting Microsoft Azure Solutions (MCP, 70-535).

Microsoft Certified Professional: Development, Extensions and Deployment for Microsoft Dynamics 365 for Finance and Operations (MCP: MB6-894).

## **KEY SKILLS**

Project Management - Agile, Waterfall, Scrum, Kanban & RAD

Programming Languages – DotNet platform (C#, ASP.NET), Php, Java, Javascript

Mobile Application Development – Android platform, windows phone and Cross-platform With Xamarin.

Web Server Technologies – Apache, Nginx, NodeJs

Operating Systems – Windows 8/8.1/10 and Unix

Version Control System – Git (GitHub, BitBucket, Gitlab)

Cloud Technologies – Microsoft Azure, AWS, RackSpace and Google Cloud Platform

Database Technologies - MYSQL, Oracle, PostgreSql, mongoDB and SQL Server

Server Management – Linux server